<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cybersecurity on Cho-Nan Tsai CTO media interviews, essays and talks</title>
    <link>https://obicho.github.io/tags/cybersecurity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cybersecurity on Cho-Nan Tsai CTO media interviews, essays and talks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:42:36 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://obicho.github.io/tags/cybersecurity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Modern “Crime and Punishment” - Joe Sullivan and Avraham Eisenberg</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/modern-crime-and-punishment-joe-sullivan-and-avraham-eisenberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/modern-crime-and-punishment-joe-sullivan-and-avraham-eisenberg/</guid>
      <description>News headline #1: Oct 5th 2022
Former Chief Security Officer Of Uber Convicted Of Federal Charges For Covering Up Data Breach Involving Millions Of Uber User Records
News Headline #2: Oct 15th 2022
Hacker behind the Mango Markets exploit keeps $47M and returns $67M to the DeFi platform after a Mango community vote; he claims his actions were legal
A high profile CISO, Sullivan, tried to do his job but ended up getting convicted in federal court.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity at Uber (or lack thereof) and Be Like Water</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/cybersecurity-at-uber/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/cybersecurity-at-uber/</guid>
      <description>Recently, Uber had a major cybersecurity incident. The hacker was able to gain access to everything, including their Amazon Web Service administrator account. This could have been really bad. Given Uber’s revenue was $17 billion (with a B) in 2021, that means – $48 million worth of revenue would have been lost a day if the hacker had shut the servers down! Imagine all those Uber drivers not being able to drive and everyday passengers getting stuck everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback to Columbia Magazine on the Cyberwarfare article</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/feedback-to-columbia-magazine-on-cyberwarfare-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/feedback-to-columbia-magazine-on-cyberwarfare-article/</guid>
      <description>I have been reading Columbia Magazine for years but this is the first time I have written a feedback to its editor. It was my reaction to a rather interesting interview with Jason Healy, a senior researcher Scholar at Columbia | SIPA (where I spent many hours studying in its library during my undergrad years). The entire interview is here.
My response to the article:
Your interview with Jason Healey couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more timely and spot on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
