<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cho-Nan Tsai CTO media interviews, essays and talks</title>
    <link>https://obicho.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cho-Nan Tsai CTO media interviews, essays and talks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:42:36 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://obicho.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hacking your tech career</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/hacking-your-tech-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/hacking-your-tech-career/</guid>
      <description>Some time in spring this year, I went to UCLA to recruit interns. While I was there, I gave a talk which ended up attracting quite a few interns working with me. Some people really enjoyed the talk so I decided to clean up my notes and publish them here. Hopefully, you will find it useful, too.
The Origin:
Many years ago, there was a college kid who was interested in an internship position at a tech startup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Columbia Venture Community: Why you will fail to build a great social impact startup</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/talks/why-you-will-fail-to-build-a-great-social-impact-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/talks/why-you-will-fail-to-build-a-great-social-impact-startup/</guid>
      <description>About the Talk For a startup founder in the impact space, it is not that difficult to just build a company. There are so many technology tools that can help a startup in the initiation phase. It almost cost just a fraction of what it used to be 10 years ago, both in terms of time and resources, to bring a product to market for validation. However, it is challenging to build a GREAT company that can make a dent in this entropic universe we live in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wire China Interview: About Beijing startup scene</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/the-wire-china-interview-about-beijing-startup-scene/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/the-wire-china-interview-about-beijing-startup-scene/</guid>
      <description>Media Interview Recently, I was interviewed for an article in The Wire China about my Beijing startup experience in 2015.
Read the full article here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to hack your career in software engineering</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/talks/la-hacks-how-to-hack-your-career-in-software-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/talks/la-hacks-how-to-hack-your-career-in-software-engineering/</guid>
      <description>About the Talk Why do some people become great software engineers very quickly, commanding high 6 figure salaries and writing code that disrupts industries? In this talk, we examine closely the career path of a software engineer and how to go about hacking it so that one can become good at what they do in a meaningful way.
Photos from the speaking event / hackathon </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenges and Opportunities in Property Tech</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/talks/challenges-opportunities-in-property-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/talks/challenges-opportunities-in-property-tech/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, I was invited to be a guest on a high profile fintech podcast called Hitechies. It was fantastic to speak with the host, Pramod Dhakal, who is based in Belgium.
We talked casually how I started in fintech with Camino Financial, then how I transitioned to proptech in the midst of the pandemic. I touched on how blockchain is revolutionizing the real estate space and my outlook on the future of crypto, online lending and fintech in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bio</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/bio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 17:17:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/bio/</guid>
      <description>Cho-Nan Tsai is an experienced product-creator and company-builder who has helped create defining infrastructure of transformative, enduring businesses in Fintech. He enjoys building and advising companies in fintech, proptech and cybersecurity. He is an expert in online lending, payment, credit card issuance, blockchain and cryptocurrency.
Currently, he is the Chief Technology Officer at Dunmore Capital. Collaborating with a team of technologists and real estate veterans, he is building the technology foundation of an online property financing company for serving professional real estate investors in the United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for a career in fintech: A conversation with Cho-Nan Tsai, a Fintech CTO</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/preparing-for-a-career-in-fintech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/preparing-for-a-career-in-fintech/</guid>
      <description>I recently gave an interview on the topic of career preparation in fintech. The interview was conducted by Trilogy Education Service which is the company that&amp;rsquo;s running Fintech Bootcamp program at Columbia Unviersity. The entire interview is here.
The article/interview was published in summer 2021 on Columbia Engineering School Bootcamp Program website</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brown Bag Tech Talks: 6 Common Traps in Data</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/talks/six-common-traps-in-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/talks/six-common-traps-in-data/</guid>
      <description>About the Talk Hosted a talk to discuss common issues when a startup is beginning to build out their data projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master Class - Building a career in software</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/talks/masterclass-building-a-career-in-software-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/talks/masterclass-building-a-career-in-software-engineering/</guid>
      <description>About the Class With professional experiences in high-flying Fortune 500 companies and tiny nobody start-ups, this battle-scarred CTO shares his wisdom from his journey on becoming a professional software engineer. In this class, you will learn tips to help you navigate this fun-filled, exciting career.
1. American dream Not your typical American dream. 2. Knowing your passion Developing a true passion can make a giant difference in your career. 3. Choosing a programming language So, which one?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crafting a Life-Changing Tech Internship Experience</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/talks/crafting-a-life-changing-tech-internship-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/talks/crafting-a-life-changing-tech-internship-experience/</guid>
      <description>Slides PDF
About the Talk Every great career begins with a dream. However, that alone is often not enough. A dreamer must be given the opportunity to try, to fail and to succeed. In 1999, I was fortunate enough to go to Tokyo for a summer internship. That’s where I met Joi Ito, got exposed to open source software for the first time and much more. It was a life-changing experience and even today I continue to cherish it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to (gracefully) jump start data science initiatives at a start-up</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/talks/how-to-gracefully-jump-start-data-science-initiatives-at-a-start-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/talks/how-to-gracefully-jump-start-data-science-initiatives-at-a-start-up/</guid>
      <description>Conference 1
Conference 2
Slides for IDEAS data science talk PPTX
Slides for IDEAS data science talk ODP
Slides for IDEAS data science talk PDF
About the Talk While machine learning and artificial intelligence can deliver a ton of value to businesses, there are still many businesses today struggling to get started with data science initiatives. Do you buy data or collect data? What type of talent to hire to get started on the first project?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Letter: Reflecting on the recruiting event at Caltech</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/open_letter_reflecting_on_the_recruiting_event_at_caltech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/open_letter_reflecting_on_the_recruiting_event_at_caltech/</guid>
      <description>Hello Team,
Today we had a recruiting event at Caltech (https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/California_Institute_of_Technology) and I was humbled by the experience.
It was intimidating at first. For the very first time, I saw Camino Financial trying to recruit, in the physical world, alongside great technology giants like Google, Facebook and Activision. I was literally flanked by a Google booth to my right and a Facebook/Instagram booth to my left. To make matters worse, I was outnumbered (each company had at least 4 engineers per booth) and I was a little late to the campus (carried our poster and my computer monitor on my own while trying to find parking, after our sprint planning meeting).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transformation</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/transformation/</guid>
      <description>A message sent through Slack to the team announcing an internship graduation.
A long long time ago, there was a boy who wasn’t fortunate in his career. After graduating from college, he had been in transition a few times, working on stuff that was neither meaningful nor rewarding.
One day, he came across a job posting at Camino for an internship opportunity. In winter, we interviewed him but we didn’t bring him onboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Gentle Introduction to Quantum Computing</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/talks/a-gentle-introduction-to-quantum-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/talks/a-gentle-introduction-to-quantum-computing/</guid>
      <description>About the Talk Quantum computers could spur the development of new breakthroughs in science, medications to save lives, machine learning methods to diagnose illnesses sooner, materials to make more efficient devices and structures, financial strategies to live well in retirement, and algorithms to quickly direct resources such as ambulances.
But what exactly is quantum computing, and what does it take to achieve these quantum breakthroughs? This talk will provide a gentle introduction to those that are interested in this new computing frontier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback to Columbia Magazine on the Cyberwarfare article</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/feedback-to-columbia-magazine-on-cyberwarfare-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/feedback-to-columbia-magazine-on-cyberwarfare-article/</guid>
      <description>I have been reading Columbia Magazine for years but this is the first time I have written a feedback to its editor. It was my reaction to a rather interesting interview with Jason Healy, a senior researcher Scholar at Columbia | SIPA (where I spent many hours studying in its library during my undergrad years). The entire interview is here.
My response to the article:
Your interview with Jason Healey couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more timely and spot on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How a fintech company ended up next to Skid Row</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/how-a-fintech-company-ended-up-next-to-skid-row/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/how-a-fintech-company-ended-up-next-to-skid-row/</guid>
      <description>A sickly-looking man, walking like a zombie, crossed my path in the middle of the road as I drove through Skid Row to get to office. While waiting for him to pass, I looked to the left and only to find more disturbing scenes: a few homeless people in a tent shooting drugs up their arms and a soup kitchen filled with people whose despair-stricken eyes were staring right back at me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A CTO&#39;s internship program out of a Los Angeles Startup</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/a-cto-internship-program-out-of-a-los-angeles-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/a-cto-internship-program-out-of-a-los-angeles-startup/</guid>
      <description>In 1999 while still a sophomore in college, I was given a chance that completely changed the course of my life. I met Kaoru Hayashi, the CEO and co-founder of a Tokyo tech startup called Digital Garage (now a publicly traded company in Japan) and he offered me a 3-month internship at his startup in Tokyo. Till this date, I still cherish every moment of that internship experience - learning how to code for the first time in Python and Zope, being exposed to open source technologies, meeting up with Joi Ito (then an entrepreneur, now a director at MIT Media Lab), supporting a live web coverage at Fuji Rock concert, hanging out with cool Tokyo teenagers and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lainto Coalition</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/talks/panelist-latino-coalition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/talks/panelist-latino-coalition/</guid>
      <description>At a panel, discussing the importance of cybersecurity for small- and mid-size businesses. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data Opportunities in the Fintech Space</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/talks/big-data-opportunities-in-the-fintech-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/talks/big-data-opportunities-in-the-fintech-space/</guid>
      <description>About the Talk Big data has impacted fintech in many ways. Some of the most creative applications of big data technology have been in the areas of fraud detection, marketing and credit underwriting for small business loans. This talk looks at some major players and how big data is leading innovations and shaping strategies in the space.
About Camino Financial Camino Financial is a credit marketplace matching small businesses with affordable business loans, with interest rates starting at 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A CTO’s Startup Journey in Beijing Zhongguancun Science Park</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/a-cto-s-startup-journey-in-beijing-zhongguancun-science-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/a-cto-s-startup-journey-in-beijing-zhongguancun-science-park/</guid>
      <description>After 10+ hours of flight, I finally arrived in Beijing.
The invitation was hard to resist. The opportunity to start a new venture in Beijing sounded like an adventure not to be missed. This brought me to Beijing. My other co-founders literally got the keys to our loft that very same day I arrived. I was greeted by my CEO who just dashed in from the hospital as someone in his family had passed away a few hours earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
