<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fintech on Cho-Nan Tsai CTO media interviews, essays and talks</title>
    <link>https://obicho.github.io/tags/fintech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fintech on Cho-Nan Tsai CTO media interviews, essays and talks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:42:36 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://obicho.github.io/tags/fintech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Challenges and Opportunities in Property Tech</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/talks/challenges-opportunities-in-property-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/talks/challenges-opportunities-in-property-tech/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, I was invited to be a guest on a high profile fintech podcast called Hitechies. It was fantastic to speak with the host, Pramod Dhakal, who is based in Belgium.
We talked casually how I started in fintech with Camino Financial, then how I transitioned to proptech in the midst of the pandemic. I touched on how blockchain is revolutionizing the real estate space and my outlook on the future of crypto, online lending and fintech in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for a career in fintech: A conversation with Cho-Nan Tsai, a Fintech CTO</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/preparing-for-a-career-in-fintech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/preparing-for-a-career-in-fintech/</guid>
      <description>I recently gave an interview on the topic of career preparation in fintech. The interview was conducted by Trilogy Education Service which is the company that&amp;rsquo;s running Fintech Bootcamp program at Columbia Unviersity. The entire interview is here.
The article/interview was published in summer 2021 on Columbia Engineering School Bootcamp Program website</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crafting a Life-Changing Tech Internship Experience</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/talks/crafting-a-life-changing-tech-internship-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/talks/crafting-a-life-changing-tech-internship-experience/</guid>
      <description>Slides PDF
About the Talk Every great career begins with a dream. However, that alone is often not enough. A dreamer must be given the opportunity to try, to fail and to succeed. In 1999, I was fortunate enough to go to Tokyo for a summer internship. That’s where I met Joi Ito, got exposed to open source software for the first time and much more. It was a life-changing experience and even today I continue to cherish it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to (gracefully) jump start data science initiatives at a start-up</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/talks/how-to-gracefully-jump-start-data-science-initiatives-at-a-start-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/talks/how-to-gracefully-jump-start-data-science-initiatives-at-a-start-up/</guid>
      <description>Conference 1
Conference 2
Slides for IDEAS data science talk PPTX
Slides for IDEAS data science talk ODP
Slides for IDEAS data science talk PDF
About the Talk While machine learning and artificial intelligence can deliver a ton of value to businesses, there are still many businesses today struggling to get started with data science initiatives. Do you buy data or collect data? What type of talent to hire to get started on the first project?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data Opportunities in the Fintech Space</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/talks/big-data-opportunities-in-the-fintech-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/talks/big-data-opportunities-in-the-fintech-space/</guid>
      <description>About the Talk Big data has impacted fintech in many ways. Some of the most creative applications of big data technology have been in the areas of fraud detection, marketing and credit underwriting for small business loans. This talk looks at some major players and how big data is leading innovations and shaping strategies in the space.
About Camino Financial Camino Financial is a credit marketplace matching small businesses with affordable business loans, with interest rates starting at 5.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
