<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Essays on Cho-Nan Tsai CTO media interviews, essays and talks</title>
    <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Essays on Cho-Nan Tsai CTO media interviews, essays and talks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:42:36 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://obicho.github.io/essays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AI drew Steve Jobs eating sushi</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/ai-drew-steve-jobs-eating-sushi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/ai-drew-steve-jobs-eating-sushi/</guid>
      <description>Today I use an AI tool to draw a picture of Steve Jobs eating sushi. This is what I got:
Remembering what I read in Steve Jobs by Walter Isaacson, Jobs&amp;rsquo; favorite food was sushi. Although Jobs had a turbulent relationship with Lisa, he often recounted the good times while eating sushi in Tokyo with his daughter. Trust me, I have tried on a number of different AI image generator sites, including DALL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control freak</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/control-freak/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/control-freak/</guid>
      <description>Lately, admin panel seems to be a recurring theme in my life. I had a discussion with someone at a startup about which one to use.
Needless to say, there is plenty of options in the market place &amp;ndash; everything from home brew custom solution to managed services to low-code platforms. Stuff like this obviously requires some research before any commitment. Since the company needing this is a very early stage startup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A omakase sushi chef and a software engineer</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/a-sushi-chef-and-a-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/a-sushi-chef-and-a-programmer/</guid>
      <description>Lately, I have been watching Michelin star sushi chefs on Youtube preparing fish for serving omakase behind a sushi bar. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a more traditional sushi restaurant experience, omakase is the way to go. You&amp;rsquo;ll be seated at the sushi bar in front of the chef, so you can easily chat and watch as your meal is made. The chef will also likely share stories and insights about their career, adding to the overall atmosphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asking for feedback</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/asking-for-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/asking-for-feedback/</guid>
      <description>Often times, my direct reports ask for my feedback. It could be for a 1-on-1, a performance review or just a sync. Sometimes, I find it stifling though. Feedback sounds overpowering and very top down.
I love giving feedback but what I love more is having a conversation. Conversation implies there is no judgement. It is a two-way discussion. From a manager&amp;rsquo;s point of view, it gives others the freedom to express.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking your tech career</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/hacking-your-tech-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/hacking-your-tech-career/</guid>
      <description>Some time in spring this year, I went to UCLA to recruit interns. While I was there, I gave a talk which ended up attracting quite a few interns working with me. Some people really enjoyed the talk so I decided to clean up my notes and publish them here. Hopefully, you will find it useful, too.
The Origin:
Many years ago, there was a college kid who was interested in an internship position at a tech startup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wire China Interview: About Beijing startup scene</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/the-wire-china-interview-about-beijing-startup-scene/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/the-wire-china-interview-about-beijing-startup-scene/</guid>
      <description>Media Interview Recently, I was interviewed for an article in The Wire China about my Beijing startup experience in 2015.
Read the full article here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for a career in fintech: A conversation with Cho-Nan Tsai, a Fintech CTO</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/preparing-for-a-career-in-fintech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/preparing-for-a-career-in-fintech/</guid>
      <description>I recently gave an interview on the topic of career preparation in fintech. The interview was conducted by Trilogy Education Service which is the company that&amp;rsquo;s running Fintech Bootcamp program at Columbia Unviersity. The entire interview is here.
The article/interview was published in summer 2021 on Columbia Engineering School Bootcamp Program website</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Letter: Reflecting on the recruiting event at Caltech</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/open_letter_reflecting_on_the_recruiting_event_at_caltech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/open_letter_reflecting_on_the_recruiting_event_at_caltech/</guid>
      <description>Hello Team,
Today we had a recruiting event at Caltech (https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/California_Institute_of_Technology) and I was humbled by the experience.
It was intimidating at first. For the very first time, I saw Camino Financial trying to recruit, in the physical world, alongside great technology giants like Google, Facebook and Activision. I was literally flanked by a Google booth to my right and a Facebook/Instagram booth to my left. To make matters worse, I was outnumbered (each company had at least 4 engineers per booth) and I was a little late to the campus (carried our poster and my computer monitor on my own while trying to find parking, after our sprint planning meeting).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transformation</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/transformation/</guid>
      <description>A message sent through Slack to the team announcing an internship graduation.
A long long time ago, there was a boy who wasn’t fortunate in his career. After graduating from college, he had been in transition a few times, working on stuff that was neither meaningful nor rewarding.
One day, he came across a job posting at Camino for an internship opportunity. In winter, we interviewed him but we didn’t bring him onboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback to Columbia Magazine on the Cyberwarfare article</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/feedback-to-columbia-magazine-on-cyberwarfare-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/feedback-to-columbia-magazine-on-cyberwarfare-article/</guid>
      <description>I have been reading Columbia Magazine for years but this is the first time I have written a feedback to its editor. It was my reaction to a rather interesting interview with Jason Healy, a senior researcher Scholar at Columbia | SIPA (where I spent many hours studying in its library during my undergrad years). The entire interview is here.
My response to the article:
Your interview with Jason Healey couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more timely and spot on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How a fintech company ended up next to Skid Row</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/how-a-fintech-company-ended-up-next-to-skid-row/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/how-a-fintech-company-ended-up-next-to-skid-row/</guid>
      <description>A sickly-looking man, walking like a zombie, crossed my path in the middle of the road as I drove through Skid Row to get to office. While waiting for him to pass, I looked to the left and only to find more disturbing scenes: a few homeless people in a tent shooting drugs up their arms and a soup kitchen filled with people whose despair-stricken eyes were staring right back at me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A CTO&#39;s internship program out of a Los Angeles Startup</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/a-cto-internship-program-out-of-a-los-angeles-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/a-cto-internship-program-out-of-a-los-angeles-startup/</guid>
      <description>In 1999 while still a sophomore in college, I was given a chance that completely changed the course of my life. I met Kaoru Hayashi, the CEO and co-founder of a Tokyo tech startup called Digital Garage (now a publicly traded company in Japan) and he offered me a 3-month internship at his startup in Tokyo. Till this date, I still cherish every moment of that internship experience - learning how to code for the first time in Python and Zope, being exposed to open source technologies, meeting up with Joi Ito (then an entrepreneur, now a director at MIT Media Lab), supporting a live web coverage at Fuji Rock concert, hanging out with cool Tokyo teenagers and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A CTO’s Startup Journey in Beijing Zhongguancun Science Park</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/a-cto-s-startup-journey-in-beijing-zhongguancun-science-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/a-cto-s-startup-journey-in-beijing-zhongguancun-science-park/</guid>
      <description>After 10+ hours of flight, I finally arrived in Beijing.
The invitation was hard to resist. The opportunity to start a new venture in Beijing sounded like an adventure not to be missed. This brought me to Beijing. My other co-founders literally got the keys to our loft that very same day I arrived. I was greeted by my CEO who just dashed in from the hospital as someone in his family had passed away a few hours earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
