<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>startup on Cho-Nan Tsai CTO media interviews, essays and talks</title>
    <link>https://obicho.github.io/tags/startup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in startup on Cho-Nan Tsai CTO media interviews, essays and talks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:42:36 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://obicho.github.io/tags/startup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Time is of the essence</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/time-is-of-the-essence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/time-is-of-the-essence/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that AWS Lambda service bills at a granularity of 1ms. (Lambda is a compute service that lets you run code without provisioning or managing servers.)
Think about that for a second.
It’s like you don’t need to pay for a 1 gallon fresh-squeezed orange juice from Costco. Instead, you just pay for what you drink, even if it is a tiny sip. Freshness guaranteed, every time.
There are many advantages to using something like AWS Lamda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spicy duck tongue and stinky tofu</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/spicy-duck-tongue-and-stinky-tofu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/spicy-duck-tongue-and-stinky-tofu/</guid>
      <description>Before the pandemic, shopping for groceries used to be a giant production for my family. Every weekend, we would set aside a few hours, load our kids into our car, bring our shopping bags, pick some groceries at a local supermarket, bag everything, drive home, unload everything from the car, etc. And, repeat all over the following weekend. Argh!
Then, came the pandemic, and everything changed!
Instacart and other grocery shopping startups really started to enjoy a boom because nobody was going out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEO of tomorrow</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/ceo-of-tomorrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/ceo-of-tomorrow/</guid>
      <description>What percentage of Y Combinator founders are technical?
Nobody really keeps track of this data. I looked. However, based on my research, it seems that typically at least one co-founder is more on the technical side within a startup. Anecdotally, I happen to know quite a few co-founders who are engineers by training and got funding from Mucker Capital.
As more businesses become accessible online, it is almost impossible to ignore the fact that a person with a technical background is better suited to run a company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI drew Steve Jobs eating sushi</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/ai-drew-steve-jobs-eating-sushi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/ai-drew-steve-jobs-eating-sushi/</guid>
      <description>Today I use an AI tool to draw a picture of Steve Jobs eating sushi. This is what I got:
Remembering what I read in Steve Jobs by Walter Isaacson, Jobs&amp;rsquo; favorite food was sushi. Although Jobs had a turbulent relationship with Lisa, he often recounted the good times while eating sushi in Tokyo with his daughter. Trust me, I have tried on a number of different AI image generator sites, including DALL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking your tech career</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/hacking-your-tech-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/hacking-your-tech-career/</guid>
      <description>Some time in spring this year, I went to UCLA to recruit interns. While I was there, I gave a talk which ended up attracting quite a few interns working with me. Some people really enjoyed the talk so I decided to clean up my notes and publish them here. Hopefully, you will find it useful, too.
The Origin:
Many years ago, there was a college kid who was interested in an internship position at a tech startup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wire China Interview: About Beijing startup scene</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/the-wire-china-interview-about-beijing-startup-scene/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/the-wire-china-interview-about-beijing-startup-scene/</guid>
      <description>Media Interview Recently, I was interviewed for an article in The Wire China about my Beijing startup experience in 2015.
Read the full article here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Letter: Reflecting on the recruiting event at Caltech</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/open_letter_reflecting_on_the_recruiting_event_at_caltech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/open_letter_reflecting_on_the_recruiting_event_at_caltech/</guid>
      <description>Hello Team,
Today we had a recruiting event at Caltech (https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/California_Institute_of_Technology) and I was humbled by the experience.
It was intimidating at first. For the very first time, I saw Camino Financial trying to recruit, in the physical world, alongside great technology giants like Google, Facebook and Activision. I was literally flanked by a Google booth to my right and a Facebook/Instagram booth to my left. To make matters worse, I was outnumbered (each company had at least 4 engineers per booth) and I was a little late to the campus (carried our poster and my computer monitor on my own while trying to find parking, after our sprint planning meeting).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transformation</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/transformation/</guid>
      <description>A message sent through Slack to the team announcing an internship graduation.
A long long time ago, there was a boy who wasn’t fortunate in his career. After graduating from college, he had been in transition a few times, working on stuff that was neither meaningful nor rewarding.
One day, he came across a job posting at Camino for an internship opportunity. In winter, we interviewed him but we didn’t bring him onboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How a fintech company ended up next to Skid Row</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/how-a-fintech-company-ended-up-next-to-skid-row/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/how-a-fintech-company-ended-up-next-to-skid-row/</guid>
      <description>A sickly-looking man, walking like a zombie, crossed my path in the middle of the road as I drove through Skid Row to get to office. While waiting for him to pass, I looked to the left and only to find more disturbing scenes: a few homeless people in a tent shooting drugs up their arms and a soup kitchen filled with people whose despair-stricken eyes were staring right back at me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
