<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mentorship on Cho-Nan Tsai CTO media interviews, essays and talks</title>
    <link>https://obicho.github.io/categories/mentorship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mentorship on Cho-Nan Tsai CTO media interviews, essays and talks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:42:36 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://obicho.github.io/categories/mentorship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Career planning, or not</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/career-planning-or-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/career-planning-or-not/</guid>
      <description>The amazing thing about meeting people in tech is that you can put people in two camps. The first camp is the founder type: they have a strong vision and want to build something to change the world. You can feel the energy blasting from every cell when they speak.
People in the second camp are professionals. They work for wonderful corporations and they are masters in what they do. Every step of the way, they work hard to build their career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myths about software engineers</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/myths-about-software-engineers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/myths-about-software-engineers/</guid>
      <description>They are super opinionated. An engineer who likes to apply one particular technology on every problem is not a good engineer. They are just being opinionated for no good reason. A good engineer would look at the problem, analyze it and then find the best solution (tools, programming language, etc). Experienced engineers would definitely have an opinion about different technologies but they would never enforce.
They are difficult to work with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An omakase sushi chef and a software engineer</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/a-sushi-chef-and-a-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/a-sushi-chef-and-a-programmer/</guid>
      <description>Lately, I have been watching Michelin star sushi chefs on Youtube preparing fish for serving omakase behind a sushi bar. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a more traditional sushi restaurant experience, omakase is the way to go. You&amp;rsquo;ll be seated at the sushi bar in front of the chef, so you can easily chat and watch as your meal is made. The chef will also likely share stories and insights about their career, adding to the overall atmosphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asking for feedback</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/asking-for-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/asking-for-feedback/</guid>
      <description>Often times, my direct reports ask for my feedback. It could be for a 1-on-1, a performance review or just a sync. Sometimes, I find it stifling though. Feedback sounds overpowering and very top down.
I love giving feedback but what I love more is having a conversation. Conversation implies there is no judgement. It is a two-way discussion. From a manager&amp;rsquo;s point of view, it gives others the freedom to express.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking your tech career</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/hacking-your-tech-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/hacking-your-tech-career/</guid>
      <description>Some time in spring this year, I went to UCLA to recruit interns. While I was there, I gave a talk which ended up attracting quite a few interns working with me. Some people really enjoyed the talk so I decided to clean up my notes and publish them here. Hopefully, you will find it useful, too.
The Origin:
Many years ago, there was a college kid who was interested in an internship position at a tech startup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to hack your career in software engineering</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/talks/la-hacks-how-to-hack-your-career-in-software-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/talks/la-hacks-how-to-hack-your-career-in-software-engineering/</guid>
      <description>About the Talk Why do some people become great software engineers very quickly, commanding high 6 figure salaries and writing code that disrupts industries? In this talk, we examine closely the career path of a software engineer and how to go about hacking it so that one can become good at what they do in a meaningful way.
Photos from the speaking event / hackathon </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for a career in fintech: A conversation with Cho-Nan Tsai, a Fintech CTO</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/preparing-for-a-career-in-fintech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/preparing-for-a-career-in-fintech/</guid>
      <description>I recently gave an interview on the topic of career preparation in fintech. The interview was conducted by Trilogy Education Service which is the company that&amp;rsquo;s running Fintech Bootcamp program at Columbia Unviersity. The entire interview is here.
The article/interview was published in summer 2021 on Columbia Engineering School Bootcamp Program website</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master Class - Building a career in software</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/talks/masterclass-building-a-career-in-software-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/talks/masterclass-building-a-career-in-software-engineering/</guid>
      <description>About the Class With professional experiences in high-flying Fortune 500 companies and tiny nobody start-ups, this battle-scarred CTO shares his wisdom from his journey on becoming a professional software engineer. In this class, you will learn tips to help you navigate this fun-filled, exciting career.
1. American dream Not your typical American dream. 2. Knowing your passion Developing a true passion can make a giant difference in your career. 3. Choosing a programming language So, which one?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crafting a Life-Changing Tech Internship Experience</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/talks/crafting-a-life-changing-tech-internship-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/talks/crafting-a-life-changing-tech-internship-experience/</guid>
      <description>Slides PDF
About the Talk Every great career begins with a dream. However, that alone is often not enough. A dreamer must be given the opportunity to try, to fail and to succeed. In 1999, I was fortunate enough to go to Tokyo for a summer internship. That’s where I met Joi Ito, got exposed to open source software for the first time and much more. It was a life-changing experience and even today I continue to cherish it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transformation</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/transformation/</guid>
      <description>A message sent through Slack to the team announcing an internship graduation.
A long long time ago, there was a boy who wasn’t fortunate in his career. After graduating from college, he had been in transition a few times, working on stuff that was neither meaningful nor rewarding.
One day, he came across a job posting at Camino for an internship opportunity. In winter, we interviewed him but we didn’t bring him onboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A CTO&#39;s internship program out of a Los Angeles Startup</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/a-cto-internship-program-out-of-a-los-angeles-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/a-cto-internship-program-out-of-a-los-angeles-startup/</guid>
      <description>In 1999 while still a sophomore in college, I was given a chance that completely changed the course of my life. I met Kaoru Hayashi, the CEO and co-founder of a Tokyo tech startup called Digital Garage (now a publicly traded company in Japan) and he offered me a 3-month internship at his startup in Tokyo. Till this date, I still cherish every moment of that internship experience - learning how to code for the first time in Python and Zope, being exposed to open source technologies, meeting up with Joi Ito (then an entrepreneur, now a director at MIT Media Lab), supporting a live web coverage at Fuji Rock concert, hanging out with cool Tokyo teenagers and more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
