<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>recruiting on Cho-Nan Tsai CTO media interviews, essays and talks</title>
    <link>https://obicho.github.io/tags/recruiting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in recruiting on Cho-Nan Tsai CTO media interviews, essays and talks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:42:36 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://obicho.github.io/tags/recruiting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Open Letter: Reflecting on the recruiting event at Caltech</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/open_letter_reflecting_on_the_recruiting_event_at_caltech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/open_letter_reflecting_on_the_recruiting_event_at_caltech/</guid>
      <description>Hello Team,
Today we had a recruiting event at Caltech (https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/California_Institute_of_Technology) and I was humbled by the experience.
It was intimidating at first. For the very first time, I saw Camino Financial trying to recruit, in the physical world, alongside great technology giants like Google, Facebook and Activision. I was literally flanked by a Google booth to my right and a Facebook/Instagram booth to my left. To make matters worse, I was outnumbered (each company had at least 4 engineers per booth) and I was a little late to the campus (carried our poster and my computer monitor on my own while trying to find parking, after our sprint planning meeting).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A CTO&#39;s internship program out of a Los Angeles Startup</title>
      <link>https://obicho.github.io/essays/a-cto-internship-program-out-of-a-los-angeles-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:42:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obicho.github.io/essays/a-cto-internship-program-out-of-a-los-angeles-startup/</guid>
      <description>In 1999 while still a sophomore in college, I was given a chance that completely changed the course of my life. I met Kaoru Hayashi, the CEO and co-founder of a Tokyo tech startup called Digital Garage (now a publicly traded company in Japan) and he offered me a 3-month internship at his startup in Tokyo. Till this date, I still cherish every moment of that internship experience - learning how to code for the first time in Python and Zope, being exposed to open source technologies, meeting up with Joi Ito (then an entrepreneur, now a director at MIT Media Lab), supporting a live web coverage at Fuji Rock concert, hanging out with cool Tokyo teenagers and more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
